CURRICULUM VITAE

I am educated to a Bachelor's degree level in IT Management. I previously worked in the manufacturing industry as a Production Manager, where during my time here I proved my worth by been promoted 2 times and responsible for managing 50 staff members, however I am passionate to start a career in IT so undertook a study program to prepare me for the IT Support sector. I have already had experience in this industry in 2013/2014 where I undertook a year at St Leger Homes in Doncaster working as part of their customer support team.

Between the December 2018 and August 2019 I spent 7 months travelling in which I visited 10 countries around the world (Thailand, Vietnam, Indonesia, Philippines, Australia, New Zealand, Argentina, Bolivia, Peru and Colombia).

I recently graduated from an IT Technician Traineeship specialising in troubleshooting hardware and software issues through a series of courses, practical work and official certifications. I am a real people person with excellent communication skills at all levels. I am confident that I will hit the ground running and be an asset to your organisation.

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: Sam Bancroft

RESIDES: Keighley

CONTACT DETAILS: (M) 07852 289833

(E) s.bancroft8@icloud.com

IT TECHNICIAN TRAINEESHIP IT Career Switch Ltd

IT Technician Traineeship August 2019 - November 2019

The IT Technician Traineeship specialised in preparing me for the IT Support sector through a series of intense courses and practical application.

Courses studied included:

CompTIA A+, Network+, Security+ MCSA Microsoft Windows 7 & 10

Cisco CCENT

- Installing, Configuring & migrating windows 7 and 10 Operating Systems
- Configuring Security systems & windows firewall
- Troubleshooting common system problems
- Configuring and managing printers, configuring mobile devices
- Configure, manage, and maintain essential network devices
- Design and implementing a functional network
- Active Directory unlocking user accounts, resetting passwords, searching users
- Implement network security, standards, and protocols

I have recently fully passed my CompTIA A+ qualifications specialising in troubleshooting hardware and Software issues. More information on this certification can be found at: https://certification.comptia.org/certifications/a

2019: CompTIA A+ 220-1001 & 1002

SYSTEMS EXPERIENCE: replacement

Windows desktop systems, install, patching, troubleshooting, hardware

Extensive experience with the Microsoft Office suite Thorough understanding of computer, networking and security concepts Working knowledge of Windows XP, Vista, 7, 8/8.1, 10,

CAREER HISTORY:

Sept 2016 - Dec 2018 **POSITION HELD:**

Fibreline Ltd Cut & Sew Department Production Manager

- Planning departments' daily production in line with demand
- Managing 3 supervisors and 50+ department staff on a day to day
- Overseeing the production of sewn cases
- Liaising with filling department supervisors (internal customers) to ensure they can run their departments efficiently and in line with
- Placing orders with external suppliers (both local & International) for contracted out work and raw materials
- Accountable for the overall housekeeping of the department
- Responsible for risk assessments as well as the full training of emplovees
- Directly involved in the reorganisation & amalgamation of two separate departments that were previously split across the production
- Playing a key role in the continual improvement project with the MTC (Manufacturing Technology Centre) to implement lean manufacturing principles to improve the systems on the shop floor
- The successful reduction of Sewn Case Stock by £20,000 whilst still keeping in line with production demands

Sep 2015 - Sep 2016 **POSITION HELD:**

Fibreline Ltd Technical Development Assistant

- Implementing and maintaining product specifications in our IT systems and CAD systems (import, scan, digitise, create)
- Supporting the Product Development Department

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015 **POSITION HELD:**

Fibreline Ltd General Management Development Assistant

• Responsible for multiple shop floor functions to get a feel for the products and processes that were used throughout the organisation

Sep 2013 - Aug 2014 **POSITION HELD:**

St Leger Homes of Doncaster **IT Business Support Assistant**

- Assisting in the provision of first line support to St Leger Staff
- Managing the pool of ICT equipment, ensuring security and accurate records are kept
- Developing and Supporting MS Access databases
 Contributing towards the delivery of actions included within the ICT Strategy Action Plan

EDUCATION:

Sheffield Hallam University

BSc (Hons) IT Management course (Achieved 2:1)

Bradford Grammar School

3 A Levels 10 GCSEs

HOBBIES/INTERESTS:

- One of my main interests outside work lies in the fitness industry, I
 regularly visit the gym which I enjoy for not only the self
 improvement but being able to see the progression I can make over a
 period of time.
- I enjoy taking on new activities which has been evident throughout my travelling in early 2019 as I have been sky diving, bungee jumping, caving and enjoyed many other new experiences.